to L. A county has declared a state of
emergency following recent immigration
raids.
It offers expanded financial aid to renters who are struggling
financially due to immigration arrests.
Landlords and apartment owner
associations are opposed.
K T L A's Jean Kang in the newsroom now with the
latest on that forest.
Jean, good morning.
Good morning, Jessica and frank
L. A county declared a state of emergency due to federal immigration
raids.
The board of supervisors voted to take action helping families who
have faced major financial burdens.
L. A county is officially in a local
emergency over federal ice raids that
have been taking place since summer.
The board of supervisors is moving forward this morning.
They voted 4 to
1 yesterday,
saying the raids put thousands of families in financial
danger.
The declaration lets the county take advantage of state money and
outside resources for county relief,
legal aid and even buying food.
For months,
families have been living under threat.
Workers have been kidnapped from job sites and
children have been coming home to empty dinner tables.
Los Angeles County has the responsibility to protect every resident
no matter where they come from or what papers they carry.
Declaring a local emergency allows us to
move faster to meet that responsibility.
And for those who want to apply an online portal
for rent help should take off in a couple of months.
But some landlords this morning are worried that this could lead to
another eviction moratorium like the one we had during the pandemic.
Supervisor Catherine Barger was the only no vote questioning
if this emergency declaration really changes anything or if it
just invites legal challenges from the Trump administration.
During open comment,
there was a mix of opinions from residents.
An emergency declaration is only needed to
pass another countywide eviction moratorium.
A third eviction moratorium will be the death
blow to many mom and pop owners struggling
from years of unpaid rent from the pandemic and the wildfires.
Just last night on Fox News,
Sean Hannity had US Attorney Pam Bondi on
his show and they talked about LA County's
state of emergency not holding back.
In LA,
they declare a state of emergency and to
aid residents hit by immigration rates.
How madam attorney general,
how is that not aiding and abetting and law breaking?
It is, Sean,
it is.
Reporting in the newsroom, Jean Kang,
Jessica and Frank, back to you.